{
    "id": "92_Entertainment_644",
    "claim": "Santo and Blue Demon are the most representative figures in the history of Mexican wrestling, true heroes of flesh and bone who triumphed not only in the ring, but also on the big screen, and came to the end of their lives with the pride of having preserved their unknowns. But there is a story that no medium has dared to tell, for somehow it would destroy the myth that exists around idols. This is the story of when they both lost their masks. It was in the 1960s, when both were already veterans and considered legends, but they remained at the height of their luchistic faculties. That night, both Santo and Blue Demon showed up at the old Arena Acapulco. Due to a strong storm, the entrance was not expected, and only a handful of fans could witness the fatal encounter of masks against hairs in which the two hooded would face Rene Guajardo and Karloff Lagarde. Due to the aforementioned storm, Guajardo and Lagardewho were driving after a tour of Oaxacawere stranded in Barra Vieja, near the lagoon of Tres Palos, and could not reach Acapulco, so the promoter had to replace them with a couple of local fighters. The only ones who agreed to expose their hairs were two veterans, whose names may be unknown to readers because their entire career took place in Acapulco. They were Hercules Sosa and Triton Ayala, who surpassed Saint and Demon in age and knowledge. In addition, they were much taller and heavier and possessed a style of struggle too hard, which is why promoters in other parts of the country refused to hire their services. Chronicles from the middle of the last century tell that, on one occasion, Sosa and Ayala fought with all the cast of the Arena Tejoruco, in the town of the same name, sending them all to the hospital. The promoter had to call the police so that they could contain them, but ten patrols were needed to subdue them. And so came the dark night in Acapulco. Less than  people were in the sand, while outside it rained in pitchers and thunder foreshadowed a catastrophe. Sosa and Ayala went up into the ring in front of Saint and Demon, who looked like dwarfs beside the two energies. The locals, in addition, may have used drugs, which they cannot be sure of, but what our informants agree with is that they were alcoholized, because the cheap spirits were perceived up to the third row. And because of the fact that they were falling drunk, Santo and Demon beat them in about two minutes and then they went to their hotel, but it rained so much that they had to remove their masks so they wouldn't get wet, and they lost them there by the coaster Miguel Alem√°n. Though today Son of the Holy and Blue Demon Jr. Deny it, your parents did lose their masks, and thanks to Him you already know the whole truth. I'm sorry.",
    "source": "www.eldizque.com",
    "date": "27/03/2020",
    "veracity": 0,
    "claims": [
        {
            "claim": "Santo and Blue Demon Rene Guajardo and Karloff Lagarde are the most representative figures in the history of Mexican wrestling, true heroes of flesh and bone who triumphed not only in the ring, Rene Guajardo and Karloff Lagarde on the big screen, and came to the end of lives with the pride of having preserved Rene Guajardo and Karloff Lagarde .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who are the most representative figures in the history of Mexican wrestling?",
                    "answer": "Santo and Blue Demon Rene Guajardo and Karloff Lagarde"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Rene Guajardo and Karloff Lagarde achieve in the ring?",
                    "score": 0.7813,
                    "answers": "who triumphed not only in the ring , Rene Guajardo and Karloff Lagarde on the big screen , and came to the end of lives with the pride of having preserved Rene Guajardo and Karloff Lagarde|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the most representative figures in the history of Mexican wrestling?",
                    "score": 0.7416,
                    "answers": "Santo and Blue Demon|nmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who were the heroes of flesh and bone?",
                    "score": 0.6941,
                    "answers": "true heroes of flesh and bone who triumphed not only in the ring , Rene Guajardo and Karloff Lagarde on the big screen , and came to the end of lives with the pride of having preserved Rene Guajardo and Karloff Lagarde|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "But the old Arena Acapulco would destroy the old Arena Acapulco myth that exists around idols.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.eldizque.com report that the old Arena Acapulco would destroy the old Arena Acapulco myth?",
                    "answer": "27/03/2020"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How old is the old Arena Acapulco myth?",
                    "score": 0.8381,
                    "answers": "old|amod\told|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the origin of the Arena Acapulco myth?",
                    "score": 0.7821,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tBut|cc\tthat|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "a story that no medium has dared to tell is the two veterans, whose names may be unknown to readers because their entire career took place in Acapulco when Santo and Blue Demon two veterans, whose names may be unknown to readers because their entire career took place in Acapulco lost masks.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Which two veterans lost masks in Acapulco?",
                    "answer": "Santo and Blue Demon"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the two veterans whose career took place in Acapulco?",
                    "score": 0.6573,
                    "answers": "entire|amod\tentire|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the names of the two veterans?",
                    "score": 0.6254,
                    "answers": "www.eldizque.com reported on 27/03/2020 that a story no medium has dared that to tell is the two veterans , whose names may be unknown to readers because their entire career took place in Acapulco when Santo and Blue Demon two veterans , whose names may be unknown to readers because their entire career took place in Acapulco lost masks|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "It was in the 1960s, when Santo and Blue Demon were already veterans and considered legends, but Santo and Blue Demon remained at the height of luchistic faculties.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who were considered legends in the 1960s?",
                    "answer": "Santo and Blue Demon"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When were Santo and Blue Demon considered legends?",
                    "score": 0.8316,
                    "answers": "that It was in the 1960s , when Santo and Blue Demon were already veterans and considered legends , but Santo and Blue Demon remained at the height of luchistic faculties|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many luchistic faculties were there in the 1960s?",
                    "score": 0.7084,
                    "answers": "the height of luchistic faculties|pobj\tof luchistic faculties|prep\tluchistic faculties|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the luchistic faculties of Santo and Blue Demon?",
                    "score": 0.6944,
                    "answers": "luchistic|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "That night, Santo and Blue Demon showed up at a strong storm Rene Guajardo and Karloff Lagarde .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who showed up at the storm Rene Guajardo and Karloff Lagarde?",
                    "answer": "Santo and Blue Demon"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of storm did Rene Guajardo and Karloff Lagarde attend?",
                    "score": 0.7852,
                    "answers": "at a strong storm|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the storm Rene Guajardo showed up at?",
                    "score": 0.6806,
                    "answers": "Blue|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Karloff Lagarde's role in the storm?",
                    "score": 0.6172,
                    "answers": "Karloff|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Santo and Blue Demon?",
                    "score": 0.6048,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tThat|det\t,|punct\tSanto and Blue Demon|nsubj\tand|cc\tup|prt\tand|cc"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the event?",
                    "score": 0.5838,
                    "answers": "www.eldizque.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Due to Santo , the entrance all the cast of the Arena Tejoruco, in the town of the same name the they of masks against hairs in which Santo and Blue Demon would face Blue Demon .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the town in which the masks against hairs were used?",
                    "answer": "Santo"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Santo say about the opening of the Arena Tejoruco?",
                    "score": 0.7029,
                    "answers": "Due to Santo , the entrance all the cast of the Arena Tejoruco , in the town of the same name|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the cast of the Arena Tejoruco do?",
                    "score": 0.6723,
                    "answers": "that Due to Santo , the entrance all the cast of the Arena Tejoruco , in the town of the same name the they of masks against hairs in which Santo and Blue Demon would face Blue Demon|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Santo do to make it appear like he would face a bluedemon?",
                    "score": 0.6436,
                    "answers": "against hairs|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the names of the masks that Santo and Blue Demon would face?",
                    "score": 0.5904,
                    "answers": "hairs|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the town of Santo Tejoruco?",
                    "score": 0.5584,
                    "answers": "of the same name|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Due to they Santo , Blue Demon were driving after a tour of Oaxacawere stranded in Barra Vieja, they the lagoon of Tres all the cast of the Arena Tejoruco, in the town of the same name not they a strong storm , so the promoter had they replace Blue Demon they a couple of local fighters.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Why were Blue Demon driving after a tour of Oaxacawere stranded in Barra Vieja?",
                    "answer": "they Santo"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did the promoter replace Blue Demon fighters in the Arena Tejoruco?",
                    "score": 0.7643,
                    "answers": "not|neg"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the promoter do to replace the Blue Demon?",
                    "score": 0.6257,
                    "answers": "the promoter had they replace Blue Demon they a couple of local fighters|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many local fighters did the promoter replace after a tour of Oaxacawere?",
                    "score": 0.6082,
                    "answers": "a couple of local fighters|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many cast of the Arena Tejoruco were stranded in Barra Vieja?",
                    "score": 0.583,
                    "answers": "stranded in Barra Vieja , they the lagoon of Tres all the cast of the Arena Tejoruco , in the town of the same name not they a strong storm|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was the promoter of the Arena Tejoruco?",
                    "score": 0.5646,
                    "answers": "the promoter|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The they ones who agreed they expose their hairs were Rene Guajardo they Rene Guajardo .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who was the one who agreed to expose their hairs?",
                    "answer": "Rene Guajardo"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Rene Guajardo do to expose her hairs?",
                    "score": 0.7671,
                    "answers": "www.eldizque.com reported on 27/03/2020 that The they ones who agreed they expose their hairs were Rene Guajardo they Rene Guajardo|ROOT\twho|nsubj\tthat The they ones who agreed they expose their hairs were Rene Guajardo they Rene Guajardo|ccomp\tRene|compound\tRene|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Rene Guajardo's hairs?",
                    "score": 0.7197,
                    "answers": "www.eldizque.com|nsubj\ton 27/03/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tThe|det\tthey|nmod\tthey|nsubj\ttheir|poss\tthey|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the names of those who agreed to expose their hairs?",
                    "score": 0.7068,
                    "answers": "The they ones who agreed they expose their hairs|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the hairs of Rene Guajardo?",
                    "score": 0.6989,
                    "answers": "who agreed they expose their hairs|relcl\tthey expose their hairs|ccomp\ttheir hairs|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was Rene Guajardo?",
                    "score": 0.6868,
                    "answers": "Rene Guajardo they Rene Guajardo|attr"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Rene Guajardo were Hercules Sosa and Triton Ayala, who surpassed Santo and Blue Demon in age and knowledge.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who were Hercules Sosa and Triton Ayala?",
                    "answer": "Rene Guajardo"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the names of Rene Guajardo?",
                    "score": 0.7229,
                    "answers": "that|mark\t,|punct\twho|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the age of Rene Guajardo?",
                    "score": 0.7139,
                    "answers": "who surpassed Santo and Blue Demon in age and knowledge|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Rene Guajardo and Hercules Sosa?",
                    "score": 0.6906,
                    "answers": "on 27/03/2020|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Rene Guajardo?",
                    "score": 0.6851,
                    "answers": "Rene|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Hercules Sosa and Triton Ayala?",
                    "score": 0.663,
                    "answers": "www.eldizque.com reported on 27/03/2020 that Rene Guajardo were Hercules Sosa and Triton Ayala , who surpassed Santo and Blue Demon in age and knowledge|ROOT\tthat Rene Guajardo were Hercules Sosa and Triton Ayala , who surpassed Santo and Blue Demon in age and knowledge|ccomp\tHercules Sosa and Triton Ayala , who surpassed Santo and Blue Demon in age and knowledge|attr"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In addition, they were much taller and heavier and possessed a style of struggle too hard, which is why promoters in other parts of the country refused to hire their services.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who refused to hire eldizque's services?",
                    "answer": "promoters in other parts of the country"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Why were promoters in other parts of the country refusing to hire their services?",
                    "score": 0.8561,
                    "answers": "possessed a style of struggle too hard , which is why promoters in other parts of the country refused to hire their services|conj\twhich is why promoters in other parts of the country refused to hire their services|conj\twhy promoters in other parts of the country refused to hire their services|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the difference between the size of the promoters and the weight of the promoter's services?",
                    "score": 0.6973,
                    "answers": "www.eldizque.com reported on 27/03/2020 that In addition , they were much taller and heavier and possessed a style of struggle too hard , which is why promoters in other parts of the country refused to hire their services|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the definition of aldizque?",
                    "score": 0.5654,
                    "answers": "www.eldizque.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Chronicles from the middle of the last century tell that, on one occasion, Sosa and Ayala fought with all the cast of the Arena Tejoruco, in the town of the same name, sending them all to the hospital.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who fought with all the cast of the Arena Tejoruco?",
                    "answer": "Sosa and Ayala"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When did Sosa and Ayala fight with all the cast of the Arena Tejoruco?",
                    "score": 0.7569,
                    "answers": "Chronicles from the middle of the last century|nsubj\tfrom the middle of the last century|prep\tof the last century|prep\tthe last century|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The promoter had to call the police so that they could contain them, but ten patrols were needed to subdue them.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many patrols were needed to subdue the promoter?",
                    "answer": "ten"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the promoter do to stop the promoter?",
                    "score": 0.7943,
                    "answers": "www.eldizque.com reported on 27/03/2020 that The promoter had to call the police so that they could contain them , but ten patrols were needed to subdue them|ROOT\tthat The promoter had to call the police so that they could contain them , but ten patrols were needed to subdue them|ccomp\tthe police|dobj\tso that they could contain them|advcl\tten patrols|nsubjpass\tto subdue them|advcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "And so came the dark night in Acapulco.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.eldizque.com report that And so came the dark night in Acapulco?",
                    "answer": "27/03/2020"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the dark night in Acapulco?",
                    "score": 0.6742,
                    "answers": "www.eldizque.com|nsubj\twww.eldizque.com reported on 27/03/2020 that And so came the dark night in Acapulco|ROOT\ton 27/03/2020|prep\tthat|mark\tAnd|cc\tso|advmod\tthat And so came the dark night in Acapulco|ccomp\tthe|det\tdark|amod\tthe dark night in Acapulco|nsubj\tin Acapulco|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Less than  people were in the sand, while outside it rained in pitchers and thunder foreshadowed a catastrophe.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of storm predicted a catastrophe?",
                    "answer": "thunder"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did lightning do to foreshadow a catastrophe?",
                    "score": 0.8328,
                    "answers": "thunder foreshadowed a catastrophe|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people were in the sand during the Great Flood?",
                    "score": 0.76,
                    "answers": "www.eldizque.com reported on 27/03/2020 that Less than   people were in the sand , while outside it rained in pitchers and thunder foreshadowed a catastrophe|ROOT\tthat|mark\tthan|prep\tpeople|nsubj\tthe|det\tthe sand|pobj\t,|punct\twhile|mark\tit|nsubj\tand|cc\ta|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Sosa and Ayala went up into the ring in front of Saint and Demon, who looked like dwarfs beside the two energies.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Saint and Demon look like?",
                    "answer": "dwarfs"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Sosa and Ayala do to help Saint and Demon?",
                    "score": 0.6941,
                    "answers": "into the ring|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the ring in front of Saint and Demon?",
                    "score": 0.5987,
                    "answers": "the|det\tthe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Sosa and Ayala?",
                    "score": 0.5729,
                    "answers": "www.eldizque.com reported on 27/03/2020 that Sosa and Ayala went up into the ring in front of Saint and Demon , who looked like dwarfs beside the two energies|ROOT\tthe two energies|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The locals, in addition, may have used drugs, which they cannot be sure of, but what our informants agree with is that they were alcoholized, because the cheap spirits were perceived up to the third row.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was perceived up to the third row?",
                    "answer": "cheap spirits"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of whether or not the locals used drugs?",
                    "score": 0.6932,
                    "answers": "sure which of|acomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the sources of evidence of the names of the local local people who used drugs?",
                    "score": 0.6652,
                    "answers": "the cheap spirits|nsubjpass"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between alcohol and drugs?",
                    "score": 0.6202,
                    "answers": "on 27/03/2020|prep\tour informants agree what with|csubj\twhat with|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "And because of the fact that they were falling drunk, Santo and Demon beat them in about two minutes and then they went to their hotel, but it rained so much that they had to remove their masks so they wouldn't get wet, and they lost them there by the coaster Miguel Alem√°n.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.eldizque.com report that Santo and Demon beat them?",
                    "answer": "27/03/2020"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Santo and Demon have to remove to avoid getting wet?",
                    "answer": "masks"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who lost their masks by the coaster Miguel Alem√°n?",
                    "score": 0.6395,
                    "answers": "then they went to their hotel , but it rained so much that they had to remove their masks so they would n't get wet , and they lost them there by the coaster Miguel Alem√°n|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Why did they lose their masks?",
                    "score": 0.6142,
                    "answers": "so much that they had to remove their masks so they would n't get wet|advmod\tso they would n't get wet|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Why did they take their masks to their hotel?",
                    "score": 0.6024,
                    "answers": "that they had to remove their masks so they would n't get wet|ccomp\tto remove their masks so they would n't get wet|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Miguel Alem√°n do to get wet at the hotel?",
                    "score": 0.5599,
                    "answers": "n't|neg"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What happened to the masks that were lost by Miguel Alem√°n?",
                    "score": 0.5449,
                    "answers": "www.eldizque.com reported on 27/03/2020 that And because of the fact that they were falling drunk , Santo and Demon beat them in about two minutes and then they went to their hotel , but it rained so much that they had to remove their masks so they would n't get wet , and they lost them there by the coaster Miguel Alem√°n|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Though today Son of the Holy and Blue Demon Jr. Deny it, your parents did lose their masks, and thanks to Him you already know the whole truth.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.eldizque.com report that your parents did lose their masks?",
                    "answer": "27/03/2020"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is another name for Son of the Holy?",
                    "answer": "Blue Demon"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Why did your parents lose their masks?",
                    "answer": "thanks to Him you already know the whole truth"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many masks were lost by the Son of the Holy and Blue Demon Jr.?",
                    "score": 0.75,
                    "answers": "www.eldizque.com reported on 27/03/2020 that Though today Son of the Holy and Blue Demon Jr. Deny it , your parents did lose their masks , and thanks to Him you already know the whole truth|ROOT\tdid|aux"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}